# ALEXANDER BURR

# SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Email alex@alexburr.com
GitHub alexburr

**Web** www.alexburr.com **Dribbble** pokealex

LinkedIn alexanderburr

JSFiddle alexburr

Software developer with over 25 years of experience in all phases of the software life cycle. A passion for creating a culture of design thinking and user experience focus. Enjoys opportunities to learn new technologies and new domains, and strives to foster sharing and mentorship between development colleagues. Experienced in Agile development with Scrum, works with a CI/CD mindset, and strives to establish a standard of quality and improvement in all areas of work.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### Senior Software Developer, Mindex — Rochester, NY

May 2021-present

- SOW position for a payroll, HR and benefits outsourcing service provider.
- Supported the retirement division with full-stack development for both internal business and customer-facing applications.
- Senior position included first contact for production and business UAT support, as well as supporting and guiding team members.
- New feature development, as well as legacy system uplift, in a microservice architecture on Java Spring Boot Framework, hosted on OpenShift.
- Web user interfaces for end-user retirement fund management, in a shared SPA platform utilizing AngularJS and React.

### Software Engineer, Pharos Systems International — Rochester, NY

June 2012-April 2021

- Full-stack development of cloud print management solution and secure print solution
- Included user interface design, .Net MVC web service development with C♯ and Razor, and ASP.NET Core Web API services
- Web UI development with jQuery, Kendo UI, React, Angular, and custom proprietary front-end frameworks

#### Lead Web Developer, University of Rochester Medical Center — Rochester, NY

July 2010-June 2012

- Developed intranet web applications with ASP.Net and SharePoint
- Designed web user interfaces for internal business applications
- Oversaw publishing of news content and employee recognition announcements

# Senior Web Developer, University of Rochester Medical Center - Rochester, NY

September 2007-June 2010

- Developed patient-facing web content for multiple hospital departments & centers
- Developed Health Encyclopedia using ColdFusion

Production Manager, Cazbah — Rochester, NY

September 2004–September 2007

Web Developer, Element K — Rochester, NY

October 2003-December 2003

Software Engineer, AHT — Rochester, NY

June 2000-July 2002

## **SKILLS & COMPETENCIES**

- Languages: C♯, Java, Python, JavaScript, TypeScript, SQL
- Databases: Oracle (PL/SQL), SQL Server (T-SQL), NoSQL (MongoDB), MySQL
- Frameworks and templating: Spring Boot, React, Angular JS, ASP.Net MVC, Web API, Spring, Razor, Nancy, Smarty, CodeIgniter, ColdFusion
- Unit testing: xUnit.net, Moq, Jest, jUnit, Mockito
- Content management: Umbraco, WordPress, Textpattern, and Cascade Server
- Wireframing and design: Figma, Gliffy, Axure RP, Adobe Photoshop, Visio, Balsamiq
- Version control: Git, Mercurial, Subversion, TFS
- Environments: Windows/IIS/OpenShift and Linux/Apache, AWS
- Project concepts: Life cycle methodology, needs assessment and usability, information architecture, content strategy, SEO and conversion, and analytics

# **EDUCATION**

#### **Rochester Institute of Technology**

Bachelor of Science in Information Technology, May 2000

### **REFERENCES**

Available upon request.

luna 2000 July 20